Taren Sanders

ACADEMIC RESEARCHER & DATA SCIENTIST

Institute for Positive Psychology and Education, Australian Catholic University

□ 0412 278 640 | ▼ Taren.Sanders@acu.edu.au | □ 0000-0002-4504-6008 | □ tarensanders | ♥ tarensanders

Education

Doctor of Philosophy

WESTERN SYDNEY UNIVERSITY 2016

 Thesis: Investigating associations between neighbourhood green space and weight status: A longitudinal study of Australian children aged 4 to 13 years old.

Master of Data Science (Applied)

Adelaide University 2022

Bachelor of Health Science (Honours; First Class)

WESTERN SYDNEY UNIVERSITY 2012

· Thesis: Measuring adolescent boys' physical activity: Bout length and the influence of accelerometer epoch length.

Bachelor of Health Science (PDHPE)

WESTERN SYDNEY UNIVERSITY 2011

Employment History _____

Program Leader

INSTITUTE FOR POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY AND EDUCATION, AUSTRALIAN CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY

2021-Current

- · Drive the strategic direction and focus of the research program
- Support academic and professional staff, as well as higher-degree students, within the program
- · Provide input as a member of the Institute Executive Management Committee on Institute priorities, and advocate for my research program
- Developed and implemented new project management processes, including making agile management strategies standard practice.

Deputy Program Leader

INSTITUTE FOR POSITIVE PSYCHOLOGY AND EDUCATION, AUSTRALIAN CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY

2017-2023

• Supported Program Leader to manage the research program

Research Fellow

Institute for Positive Psychology and Education, Australian Catholic University

2016-Current

- · Conduct original, high-impact, and translational research in the areas of health, education, and psychology.
- Oversee the development, evaluation, and management of multiple large-scale school-based research projects (e.g., iPLAY; 180 schools).
- · Conduct analyses of primary and secondary data, and provided statistical support to colleagues including statistics workshops.
- · Work with industry partners (NSW Department of Education, NSW Health, Sport Australia) to provide project updates and seek input.
- Author academic and non-academic outputs, including journal articles, grant applications, stakeholder reports, and data visualisations.
- · Mentor doctoral and honours students, including reviewing and evaluating their analyses and writing.

Research Summary _____

Publications	Citations	h-Index	Mean CNCI	Mean Impact	Funding
39	1639	21	1.9	Factor 7.9	> \$1 million

Technical Skills _____

Programming Languages

R, Python, Stata, Julia

Software Development

R PACKAGES (INCLUDING CRAN SUBMISSION), PYTHON PACKAGES

Statistical Methods

MACHINE LEARNING, MULTILEVEL MODELLING, INTERVENTION EVALUATION, META-ANALYSES

Research Methods

STUDY DESIGN, INTERVENTION DEVELOPMENT, ETHICS AND RECRUITMENT

Selected Publications

For a full list of publications see my full CV (bit.ly/TarenSanders).

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

Lubans, D. R., **Sanders, T.**, Noetel, M., Parker, P., McKay, H., Morgan, P., Salmon, J., Kirwan, M., Bennie, A., Peralta, L., Cinelli, R., Moodie, M., Hartwig, T., Boyer, J., Kennedy, S. G., Plotnikoff, R. C., Hansen, V., Vasconcellos, D., Lee, J., ... Lonsdale, C. (2022). Scale-up of the Internet-based Professional Learning to help teachers promote Activity in Youth (iPLAY) intervention: A hybrid type 3 implementation-effectiveness trial. *International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity*, *19*(1), 141. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-022-01371-4 | Citations: 2; JIF: 8.7; CNCI: 1.1

Antczak, D., Lonsdale, C., del Pozo Cruz, B., Parker, P., & **Sanders, T.** (2021). Reliability of GENEActiv accelerometers to estimate sleep, physical activity, and sedentary time in children. *International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity*, 18(1), 73. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-021-01143-6 | Citations: 5; JIF: 8.7; CNCI: 0.9

Noetel, M., Griffith, S., Delaney, O., Harris, N. R., **Sanders, T.**, Parker, P., del Pozo Cruz, B., & Lonsdale, C. (2021). Multimedia Design for Learning: An Overview of Reviews With Meta-Meta-Analysis. *Review of Educational Research*. https://doi.org/10.3102/00346543211052329 | Citations: 7; JIF: 11.2; CNCI: 1.1

Lee, J., **Sanders, T.**, Antczak, D., Parker, R., Noetel, M., Parker, P., & Lonsdale, C. (2021). Influences on User Engagement in Online Professional Learning: A Narrative Synthesis and Meta-Analysis. *Review of Educational Research*, 91(4), 518–576. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654321997918 | Citations: 8; JIF: 11.2; CNCI: 2.8

Hartwig, T. B., **Sanders, T.**, Vasconcellos, D., Noetel, M., Parker, P. D., Lubans, D. R., Andrade, S., Ávila-García, M., Bartholomew, J., Belton, S., Brooks, N. E., Bugge, A., Cavero-Redondo, I., Christiansen, L. B., Cohen, K., Coppinger, T., Dyrstad, S., Errisuriz, V., Fairclough, S., ... del Pozo Cruz, B. (2021). School-based interventions modestly increase physical activity and cardiorespiratory fitness but are least effective for youth who need them most: An individual participant pooled analysis of 20 controlled trials. *British Journal of Sports Medicine*, *55*(13), 721–729. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2020-102740 | Citations: 25; JIF: 18.4; CNCI: 3.5

Lonsdale, C., **Sanders, T.**, Parker, P., Noetel, M., Hartwig, T., Vasconcellos, D., Lee, J., Antczak, D., Kirwan, M., Morgan, P., Salmon, J., Moodie, M., McKay, H., Bennie, A., Plotnikoff, R. C., Cinelli, R., Greene, D., Peralta, L., Cliff, D., ... Lubans, D. R. (2021). Effect of a Scalable School-Based Intervention on Cardiorespiratory Fitness in Children: A Cluster Randomized Clinical Trial. *JAMA Pediatrics*, 175(7), 680. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics. 2021.0417 | Citations: 14; JIF: 26.1; CNCI: 3.9

Noetel, M., Griffith, S., Delaney, O., **Sanders, T.**, Parker, P., del Pozo Cruz, B., & Lonsdale, C. (2021). Video Improves Learning in Higher Education: A Systematic Review. *Review of Educational Research*, 91(2), 204–236. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654321990713 | Citations: 31; JIF: 11.2; CNCI: 4.9

Antczak, D., Lonsdale, C., Lee, J., Hilland, T., Duncan, M. J., del Pozo Cruz, B., Hulteen, R. M., Parker, P. D., & **Sanders, T.** (2020). Physical activity and sleep are inconsistently related in healthy children: A systematic review and meta-analysis. *Sleep Medicine Reviews*, *51*, 101278. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.smrv.2020.101278 | Citations: 24; JIF: 10.5; CNCI: 1.3

Sanders, T., Parker, P. D., del Pozo-Cruz, B., Noetel, M., & Lonsdale, C. (2019). Type of screen time moderates effects on outcomes in 4013 children: Evidence from the Longitudinal Study of Australian Children. *International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity*, 16(1), 117. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-019-0881-7 | Citations: 53; JIF: 8.7; CNCI: 4

Sanders, T., Feng, X., Fahey, P. P., Lonsdale, C., & Astell-Burt, T. (2015). The influence of neighbourhood green space on children's physical activity and screen time: Findings from the longitudinal study of Australian children. *International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity*, 12(1), 126. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-015-0288-z| Citations: 57; JIF: 8.7; CNCI: 2.5